<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lutheran Answers – Your Questions, Answered</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/answers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Your Questions, Answered on Lutheran Answers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 20:23:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/answers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Mormons Christians?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/answers/cults/unitarians/mormons/are-mormons-christians/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 20:44:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/answers/cults/unitarians/mormons/are-mormons-christians/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No, members of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints are not Christians.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Mormons are under the impression that they are the true Christians who have joined the true church of Jesus Christ as restored by Joseph Smith after a great apostasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, however, couldn’t be further from the truth. Mormons are actually members of a heretical non-Christian cult and are destined for eternity in Outer Darkness if they do not repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Major Problems with Mormonism&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;major-problems-with-mormonism&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#major-problems-with-mormonism&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this section I will outline some of the biggest problems with Mormonism and the things that keep them outside of the true, saving faith of Jesus Christ. Please note this section will deal with salvific issues that Mormons face – I.E. the things that prevent them from entering Heaven (the Celestial Kingdom in Mormonese), and will ultimately resign them to eternal damnation (outer darkness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Mormon Jesus&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-mormon-jesus&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-mormon-jesus&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem with Mormonism is the problem with their Jesus. Mormons will tell you that they worship the same Jesus that other Christians do. But that isn’t true. These are the issues with the Mormon view of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Unitarianism&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;unitarianism&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#unitarianism&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mormons are Unitarian heretics who deny the Trinity. They believe that Jesus is a completely separate being with a separate substance from the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They believe that both Jesus and actually Satan are literal children born of a physical, conjugal relation of Heavenly Father (what they call The Father) and Heavenly Mother (a being that does not exist).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because they believe in an ontologically different Jesus, they must – literally and necessarily – be worshipping a different Jesus than other Christians. This is generally hard for unitarians to understand because they say they believe the Bible and use the same name we do for Jesus – so why isn’t it the same?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well let’s say that when I talk about Velma from Scooby-Doo, I’m referencing this nerdy brunette from the 70s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../old-velma.webp&#34; alt=&#34;old Velma&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when you talk about Velma, you’re talking about the Indian Velma from Mindy Kaling’s HBO series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../new-velma.png&#34; alt=&#34;new Velma&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are obviously talking about two different characters. They look different, act different, are in different settings. They just share names. One could argue that the newer Velma is just an imposter TV show wearing a Scooby-Doo skin suit to try and trade off of the good name that series earned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like that. The Mormon Jesus, as they define Him, may have the same name and claim the same setting and attributes of Jesus, but it’s simply a poor copy attempting to trade on Jesus’ good name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;A better example&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;a-better-example&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#a-better-example&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since this article was originally written and published, I have conceived of an even better example than the Velma one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we both agree that our favorite movie is Ghostbusters, and we are both fans of the same movie, but when I say “Ghostbusters” I’m talking about this movie, from 1984:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../ghostbusters.gif&#34; alt=&#34;OG Ghost Busters&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when you say “Ghostbusters” you’re talking about this movie, from 2016:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;../galbusters.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Fake Ghost Busters&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we talking about the same movie? Are we fans of the same movie? But both movies have similar plots, they have a similar cast of characters, and even the same title and logo!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet these two movies are not the same movie. They’re different movies. And you can’t say that we’re both talking about the same movie just because they have the same name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same thing with Jesus. You can put Jesus in your church’s name until you’re blue in the face, you can ascribe to him all the different genealogical and historical details you want, but if we fundamentally disagree about who He is, then we are talking about different Jesuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Arianism&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;arianism&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#arianism&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Mormons are also Arian heretics. That is, they believe Jesus is just a man. In fact, they’re Super-Arians because they believe that Heavenly Father is also just a man who lived super duper good and was transformed into a god by his father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mormons maintain that God Himself is not a distinct being from man, but that men can become gods themselves. This applies to each person of the Godhead – who have already achieved deification – as well as to each and every individual on earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another way in which Mormons are worshipping an entirely different being than Christians, just with the same name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A False Plan of Salvation&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;a-false-plan-of-salvation&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#a-false-plan-of-salvation&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Mormon Plan of Salvation, as they call it, is heavily dependent on your own works. Mormons believe that Jesus came to be an example to us, not to live vicariously for us. They also believe that He died so that we could be given a chance at Heaven, and He rose from the dead so that we might be resurrected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Mormonism, there is no conquering of death. There is no eternal remission of sin. There is no subjugation of the devil and this world. There is only Jesus offering you a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a missionary put it to me this way: You really need a new job. Jesus knows a guy at the company and puts in a good word to get you an interview. But now that you have the interview it is up to you to interview well enough to get the job. And once you get the job it’s up to you to work hard enough to be promoted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and how exactly do you work hard enough?
In addition to the 10 commandments, Mormons add an additional ~600 other commands that must be kept in order to achieve perfection and reach the Celestial Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breaking of these commands is sin, and each sin pulls you away from perfection. Mormons often quote Matthew 5:48, saying that Christ commands us, “&lt;a href=&#34;https://beyeperfect.org/&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Be Ye Perfect&lt;svg class=&#34;hx:inline hx:rtl:rotate-270 hx:align-baseline&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
 &lt;path d=&#34;m9.1716 7.7574h7.0711m0 0v7.0711m0-7.0711-8.4853 8.4853&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;” here and now in this life. Those who are not perfect cannot attain all that Heavenly Father has for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ibis.utah.gov/ibisph-view/indicator/complete_profile/SuicDth.htm&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;It is no wonder Utah’s suicide rate is 50% higher than the national average&lt;svg class=&#34;hx:inline hx:rtl:rotate-270 hx:align-baseline&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
 &lt;path d=&#34;m9.1716 7.7574h7.0711m0 0v7.0711m0-7.0711-8.4853 8.4853&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Minor Problems with Mormonism&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;minor-problems-with-mormonism&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#minor-problems-with-mormonism&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section will focus on other oddities of Mormonism that don’t make much sense. These things aren’t necessarily salvific issues, but I’m sure that some of them can become that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Universal Salvation&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;universal-salvation&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#universal-salvation&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mormons believe that everyone will be saved. They have three levels of Heaven: The telestial, terrestrial, and celestial. Every single person will end up in one of the three levels of heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;You are sealed to your family, but it’s pointless.&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;you-are-sealed-to-your-family-but-its-pointless&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#you-are-sealed-to-your-family-but-its-pointless&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Heaven: Mormonism believes that you have to be sealed to your family if you want to spend eternity with them. Except you being sealed to your spouse doesn’t guarantee anything because they might not make it as far up in Heaven as you, and only those in the Celestial Kingdom get to spend forever with their families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Women have no future in heaven&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;women-have-no-future-in-heaven&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#women-have-no-future-in-heaven&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Women in Mormon heaven exist only to be bred by their husbands to create spirit children. Also, if you are a woman, and you’re sealed to your husband, and you both make it to the celestial kingdom, and you both become gods, you might not be his only bride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, it is up to the husband to call you up to that level, so he may leave you behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if you are his only bride, and he does call you up, and you both do get a planet, your only role in that planet will be producing his offspring. He gets to be the one who is actually god.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Issues&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;other-issues&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#other-issues&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are tons of other issues, such as literary and historical problems with Mormon holy books, the character of Joseph Smith, other beliefs and values of the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are too many to list here, so I advise you go read something like the CES Letter or check out resources like Truth In Love Ministries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the first of a four part episode I did with Rev. Mark Parsons of Truth in Love Ministries on the LDS faith:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NIu--rbmaOs?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Pope the Anti-Christ?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/answers/catholicism/pope-antichrist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 20:38:18 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/answers/catholicism/pope-antichrist/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/answers/pope.png&#34; alt=&#34;Is the Pope the Anti-Christ?&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calling the pope the antichrist can be a pretty divisive statement. It’s the kind of opinion that many would refrain from speaking out loud because it may put off a Catholic friend. I admit that it is a pretty incendiary thing to say, but it is a thing that must be said nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why, then, do we believe that the pope is the antichrist? Well, it is a pretty nuanced thing. First and foremost, we don’t necessarily believe that the pope is The Antichrist, though we wouldn’t be entirely shocked if it worked out that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather, we believe that the office of the papacy is, itself, anti-Christ. That is to say, the office of the pope is against Christ. This is because of Catholic teaching which places the pope as the fount and head of all church authority – instead of Christ – and sets him up to be a mediator between us and Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Lord tells us through the Apostle Paul in his first letter to Timothy, “For there is one God, and there is one mediator between God and men, the man Christ Jesus […]” (1 Tim 2:5). The Roman Catholic Church says, essentially, “And that’s true, but there is a mediator between man and Christ and that is The Pope.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now what’s funny is the Catholic church holds this position – that one must be a part of the Roman church – to be saved, but they also hold to the opposite position and believe that one need not even be a Christian to be saved. Indeed, they say that as long as you strive to live the best life you can, your life will be pleasing to God and you will be granted entrance to Heaven. I’ve even heard a Catholic priest say that one could be an atheist, vehemently denying the Lord Jesus, and still gain entrance into Heaven by living to their best interpretation of morality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, also, is anti-Christ because it takes the focus of salvation off the person and work of Jesus and places it squarely on you and your own works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the Catholic church’s teachings on salvation are anti-Christ, and their doctrines surrounding the office of the pope are anti-Christ. Necessarily, then, the person occupying the office of the pope must be an antichrist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, I do not, and would never, say that Jorge Bergoglio is the antichrist. I don’t believe he is. But until he repents and abdicates the office of pope, I must declare that Pope Francis is antichrist.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the COVID-19 vaccine the Mark of the Beast?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/answers/eschatology/covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:25:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/answers/eschatology/covid-19/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/answers/vaccine.png&#34; alt=&#34;COVID-19&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Understanding Revelation&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;understanding-revelation&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#understanding-revelation&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Mark of the Beast is a tricky subject to work through. Before writing this article I spent some time in commentaries, went through a guided Bible study, listened to a few podcasts, and read through my copies of On the Last Judgement, A Summary of Christian Doctrine, Thief in the Night, and Pieper&amp;rsquo;s Dogmatics, Vol III - all of which deal with the subject of the End Times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want you to think that this opinion, lay though it may be, is an uninformed one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eschatology&lt;/em&gt;, or the Study of the End Times, is an often very confusing subject - and modern American Evangelical Christianity has done nothing to help that. When we look at St. John&amp;rsquo;s Revelation we must keep in mind that the book itself is The Revelation of Jesus Christ, and that everything in the book is meant to reveal Christ to us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should also understand that the book itself is not set in the distant future, applicable only to the group of Christians nearing or at the Day of Judgment. Rather, it is a book meant to bless and encourage all Christians at all times and in all places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book of Revelation is a book that, chiefly, shows Christ at work, ruling and reigning in this world actively and right now in order that we might be comforted and blessed during times of tribulation. It is not a book that foretells some cataclysmic future event, at least that is not its primary purpose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Mark&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-mark&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-mark&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keeping these things in mind, we can look at The Mark and understand it to be allegorical and not literal. Again, I&amp;rsquo;m going to make use of the word &amp;ldquo;chiefly&amp;rdquo; when I say this. While there may end up being a literal Mark of the Beast one day, we should approach the text as primarily allegorical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mark is mentioned in the 13th chapter of Revelation, verses sixteen through eighteen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Also it causes all, both small and great, both rich and poor, both free and slave, to be marked on the right hand or the forehead, so that no one can buy or sell unless he has the mark, that is, the name of the beast or the number of its name. This calls for wisdom: let the one who has understanding calculate the number of the beast, for it is the number of a man, and his number is 666.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Revelation 13:16-18&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people read this passage and immediately jump to a literal sign of some sort that is literally on your actual forehead or right hand that marks you as owned by Satan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s understandable. If you just read it without any kind of hermeneutical context, it certainly looks that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it probably isn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Mark of the Lord&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-mark-of-the-lord&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-mark-of-the-lord&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The mark of the beast, mentioned in Revelation 13, is a direct contrast against the earlier Seal of the Lord on the forehead of the elect. The Lord marks us as his own in our baptisms. We are sealed by the Holy Spirit, who is the collateral we get until the day we are finally saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By way of contrast, the beast also has a seal - The Mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What is The Mark of the Beast?&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;what-is-the-mark-of-the-beast&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#what-is-the-mark-of-the-beast&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This deserves its own article, but for now it will suffice to say that the Mark of the Beast is disbelief, a rejection of the Holy Spirit, or an exaltation of the self as an idol. John clearly mentions the mark is a number, and the number is the number of a man. And we can certainly talk about how he&amp;rsquo;s being cryptic about Nero, or perhaps a future antichrist, but is also proper to understand this passage - in light of the clearer scriptures - as a warning against idolatry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Why the Vaccine isn&amp;rsquo;t the Mark&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;why-the-vaccine-isnt-the-mark&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#why-the-vaccine-isnt-the-mark&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lutheran teaching and doctrine surrounding the Mark of the Beast advocates the same position that scripture advocates: That it will be something willingly taken by those who are not saved. I phrase it this way specifically to dispel doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mark will be taken by those deceived, but it is important to note that the deception is not about the mark or its nature. Rather, the deception is about the disposition of their own soul. The deceived, in this case, are specifically deceived about their salvation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To continue with our theme of idolatry and the exaltation of the self (setting yourself up as a god in your own heart, i.e. being an abomination in the temple of the Lord ?), the deceived believe that - if Heaven is real - they will get there just fine because they&amp;rsquo;re &amp;ldquo;good people&amp;rdquo; just &amp;ldquo;living their authentic truth,&amp;rdquo; or whatever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t accidentally get the mark&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;you-cant-accidentally-get-the-mark&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#you-cant-accidentally-get-the-mark&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The spearhead of the previous paragraphs is that you can&amp;rsquo;t accidentally get the mark or be tricked into it. My pastor, who loves and cares for his congregation, got the vaccine so that he could do home visits with elderly and at risk congregants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He got the vaccine specifically so he could go administer the sacraments. To say that it&amp;rsquo;s the mark of the beast is to think that when he stands before the Throne of Judgment, God is going to say, &amp;ldquo;Sorry Joe, I know you got that vaccine because you wanted to feed my sheep, but it was actually the mark of the beast and you didn&amp;rsquo;t know it, so your baptism is nullified and now you&amp;rsquo;re going to hell.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is obviously absurd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The mark is a sign, not a cause&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-mark-is-a-sign-not-a-cause&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-mark-is-a-sign-not-a-cause&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modern Christians can believe all sorts of weird things that seem to contradict each other. For example: We know that blaspheming the Holy Spirit is the only unforgivable sin. What that consists of, exactly, needs its own article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Christians will believe that and at the same time believe the mark of the beast is some external marking, or implant, or barcode, and simultaneously believe that if you take the mark you will be damned. So they believe in two unforgivable sins: Blaspheming the Holy Spirit and taking the mark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a clear contradiction of scripture&amp;hellip; if the mark is some external thing. However, if the mark of the beast is idolatry of the self, rejection of the Holy Spirit, or general disbelief as I&amp;rsquo;ve asserted, then it is actually the same thing as the unforgivable sin. Thus having the mark doesn&amp;rsquo;t damn you, but rather means you&amp;rsquo;re damned. It is a sign of damnation, rather than a cause.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I point this out because I don&amp;rsquo;t want you to think that getting a vaccine will suddenly put your salvation in danger because it may have been the mark of the beast and you didn&amp;rsquo;t know it. The mark, I do not believe, is some external thing. And if it is, it will surely come with a known, purposeful, and conscious rejection of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;No Forehead Vaccines&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;no-forehead-vaccines&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#no-forehead-vaccines&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The people who read the scripture here overly literally are very, very quick to point out that the mark must be a literal, physical thing. Those same people will immediately jump out of rigid literalism and into allegorical interpretation when you point out that no one injects a vaccine into their right hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Well romans considered the entire arm the hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No. They didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And these mental gymnastics continue forever:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What about people who got the vaccine in their left arm, then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, well right hand just means &amp;lsquo;place of authority&amp;rsquo; in the Bible&amp;hellip;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one gets a vaccine in their forehead&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, well that just means they&amp;hellip; decided&amp;hellip; to get it&amp;hellip; with their&amp;hellip; hearts?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably my least favorite aspect of American Evangelicalism: The absolute lack of hermeneutical consistency. Things are literal when they support their views, and allegorical when they do not, and their main interpretive device is some random right-wing conspiracy blogger who claims a red heifer was just born in palestine for the first time millennia (even though they&amp;rsquo;re born every single day, and red doesn&amp;rsquo;t refer to only the color, but to a specific ritualistic state). It&amp;rsquo;s frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;In Conclusion&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;in-conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#in-conclusion&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;No the vaccine isn&amp;rsquo;t the mark of the beast. You will not be damned for all eternity if you get vaccinated against coronavirus so that you can go visit your grandparents. Whether or not you feel you should get the vaccine is a matter of Christian Freedom. COVID-19 is pretty serious and you should take it pretty seriously. But you should not let the fear of sickness distract you from the fact that in Christ you are literally immortal and now will never die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love you. God bless you.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does the Bible condemn interracial marriage?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/answers/christian-life/interracial-marriage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 18:06:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/answers/christian-life/interracial-marriage/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/answers/interracial-marriage.png&#34; alt=&#34;Interracial Marriage&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of people on the internet these days talking about interracial marriage. Especially on , where hateful, unbiblical, and satanic views about race seem to have taken a hold with disaffected men. These views seem wicked at face-value, but they purport to be Biblical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a lot said about bloodlines, and honoring your ancestors, cherry picking some very out-of-context Bible verses, and even a lot of quoting of American theologians from the 1800s and early 1900s - though, oddly enough, nothing from much older theologians, magisterial reformers, or patristic sources (hm&amp;hellip; 🤔).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to look at the issue of interracial marriage from a Scriptural, Christian perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;Faithfulness to God - The Priority of Scripture.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;faithfulness-to-god---the-priority-of-scripture&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#faithfulness-to-god---the-priority-of-scripture&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strongest testimony in scripture against interracial marriage comes from Deuteronomy chapter 7, which reads as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When the Lord your God brings you into the land which you are entering to possess and has driven out many nations before you, the Hittites and the Girgashites and the Amorites and the Canaanites and the Perizzites and the Hivites and the Jebusites, seven nations greater and mightier than you, and when the Lord your God delivers them before you and you strike them down, then you must utterly destroy them. You shall make no covenant with them nor show mercy to them. What is more, you shall not intermarry with them. You shall not give your daughters to their sons or take their daughters for your sons. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 7:1-3, MEV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is unambiguously the clearest condemnation of ethnic inter-marriage in the Bible. In fact, this scripture seems like a slam dunk condemnation of interracial or interethnic marriages. So why isn&amp;rsquo;t this the verse that is used by those who think interracial marriages are sinful? Because if you read even one verse more into the chapter you realize God isn&amp;rsquo;t forbidding these marriages because of ethnicity or race:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt; What is more, you shall not intermarry with them. You shall not give your daughters to their sons or take their daughters for your sons. For they will turn your sons away from following Me to serve other gods. Then the anger of the Lord will be inflamed against you, and He will quickly destroy you. But this is how you shall deal with them: You shall destroy their altars and break down their images and cut down their Asherim and burn their graven images with fire. For you are a holy people to the Lord your God. The Lord your God has chosen you to be His special people, treasured above all peoples who are on the face of the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Deuteronomy 7:3-6, MEV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God certainly did forbid the Israelites from marrying the people of the nations around them, but it had nothing to do with ethnicity or race. God&amp;rsquo;s primary purpose in forbidding interracial marriage for the Israelites was so that they would remain faithful to Him in worship. God, knowing all things, knew that if His people were allowed to marry pagans, then they themselves would be swayed by their paganism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone who is married understands this pretty well. Before you&amp;rsquo;re married, you have a lot of different habits and views. Quite a few of those things perish in gruesome fashion when you and your spouse move in together. You now have another person that you consider in your daily activities and living. Your habits and routines shift to accommodate this other person (as do theirs). Eventually you form a sort of synergy around all of the malleable things, wherein you come to a mutual understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem, though, centers around those non-malleable things. The non-negotiables that your spouse has. You love your spouse and often times will find yourself negotiating on topics that are non-negotiable to them, but surprisingly squishy for you when push comes to shove.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll give you a concrete example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My wife and I knew this couple, some years ago, that we had befriended. We were both in the same place in our lives: Young and married, but no kids yet. We got along well, and would often go out to eat or hang out at each other&amp;rsquo;s houses, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The major difference between my wife and I, and this couple, is that they were devout atheists, and we were devout Christians. The man had been raised an atheist. He was very intelligent and very well read philosophically. We enjoyed sparring back and forth about God. It was always friendly, and always done over cigars and bourbon. The wife, however, was raised Methodist. But she really loved this man. So when they decided they wanted to be married, she became an atheist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Something she thought was a non-negotiable was suddenly very squishy.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ended up drifting apart from this couple, but not before they had their first child. The strangest thing happened, though, when they had a kid: The wife was suddenly Methodist again! She wanted her baby baptized, and she wanted her baby raised Methodist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, the very adamant, intelligent atheist husband&amp;hellip; wait for it&amp;hellip; became a Methodist!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He converted, started going to church, had their kid baptized. Whole nine. I asked him about it and he shrugged and said, &amp;ldquo;It was important to her.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We see this very thing happening throughout Scripture. The prophet Nehemiah gives us a good (and passionate) example of this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Moreover, in those days I also saw Jews who had married the women of Ashdod, Ammon, and Moab. Half of their children spoke in the language of Ashdod, yet none of them could recognize the language of the Jews. This was true language by language. So I confronted them and cursed them. Some of the men I beat. Others, I plucked out their hair. Also, I made them swear an oath by God and said to them, “You shall neither give your daughters to their sons, nor marry their daughters to your sons or to yourselves. Did not Solomon king of Israel sin by these things? Yet among many nations there was no king like him. He was loved by his God, who made him king over all Israel. Nevertheless, foreign women caused even him to sin. Should we then listen to you, the ones doing all this great evil, who are behaving unfaithfully against our God by bedding foreign women?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Nehemiah 13:23-27, MEV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem outlined by Nehemiah isn&amp;rsquo;t that foreign women pollute the bloodline of Judah, and thus those who take foreign wives dishonor their parents and ancestors. It isn&amp;rsquo;t that God created distinct nations that He has commanded to remain unmixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem outlined by Nehemiah is that foreign wives lead faithful men to whore after foreign gods. God says this explicitly to Moses in Exodus 34, when He warns Moses not to let the people take foreign wives, yet says that they will do so anyway:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Watch yourself so that you make no covenant with the inhabitants of the land where you are going, lest it become a snare in your midst. But you shall destroy their altars, break their sacred pillars, and cut down their Asherah poles (for you shall not worship any other god, for the Lord, whose name is Jealous, is a jealous God), lest you make a covenant with the inhabitants of the land, and they prostitute themselves with their gods, and sacrifice to their gods, and someone invites you to eat of his sacrifice. And then you take of their daughters for your sons, and their daughters prostitute themselves after their gods. They will make your sons prostitute themselves after their gods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Exodus 34:12-16, MEV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Biblical Examples of Interracial Marriage&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;biblical-examples-of-interracial-marriage&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#biblical-examples-of-interracial-marriage&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is also important, in this discussion, to look at various concrete examples of known interracial marriage that we have in the Bible. You would imagine that if this is a sinful action, and the Bible has several examples of it happening, that it would condemn that action. And yet, none of the examples of interracial marriage that explicitly occur in the Bible are condemned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the opposite, actually! They are all praised, and in one case, those who condemn the marriage because it is an inter-ethnic marriage are themselves admonished for sinful behavior!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ruth &amp;amp; Boaz&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;ruth--boaz&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#ruth--boaz&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ruth is a Moabite woman who famous marries a prominent Jew, Boaz, in the Old Testament book of Ruth. Ruth is important in the Jewish faith as being the reason King David, the greatest Jewish king, even existed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we are told in Ruth, Ruth is the mother of Obed, and Obed the father of Jesse, and Jesse the father of King David (Ruth 4:17, 21-22).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why wasn&amp;rsquo;t Boaz&amp;rsquo;s marriage to Ruth sinful? Because Ruth wasn&amp;rsquo;t a pagan or worshipper of false gods! Ruth has a very dramatic conversion moment in Chapter 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Naomi said, “Look, your sister-in-law has returned to her people and her gods. Return with her!” But Ruth said, “Do not urge me to leave you or to turn back from following you. For wherever you go, I will go, and wherever you stay, I will stay. Your people shall be my people and your God my God.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;Ruth 1:15-16, MEV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prohibition against marrying foreigners came from God&amp;rsquo;s jealousy and His desire to keep His people from worshipping the gods of foreigners. This is not a problem if the foreigner worships the One True God, and thus the prohibition does not apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rahab the Prostitute&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;rahab-the-prostitute&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#rahab-the-prostitute&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rahab was a prostitute and inn-keeper in Jericho who aided Joshua&amp;rsquo;s spies by hiding them from the men of the land and helping them escape a search party sent after them. If you read the account (found in Joshua 2) it is pretty clear that Rahab very quickly became a believer in the One True God after the Fear of Him fell upon her city. According to Matthew, she then goes on to marry Salmon, of Judah, and gives birth to the aforementioned Boaz (Matthew 1:5).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more interesting is that, of the 5 women mentioned in the genealogy of Jesus, 2 of them are non-Jew foreigners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet some folks out there would have you believe that God is vehemently against interracial marriage and considers it sinful and abominable, but for some reason allowed 20% of His own genealogy to be interracial?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And not only is she not a Jew, Rahab is a Canaanite. There are those out there who claim that anyone from the lineage of Ham ought to be a slave and is cursed by God forever. And yet Christ&amp;rsquo;s own ancestor is a Canaanite woman.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christ is truly the curse-breaker and the death of death for all men.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Moses &amp;amp; The Cushite&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;moses--the-cushite&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#moses--the-cushite&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Numbers Chapter 12 outlines a very interesting event where we&amp;rsquo;re told about Moses taking a Cushite woman (a black Ethiopian) to be his wife. His brother Aaron and his sister in law Miriam come to him and criticize him before all the people of Israel for taking a Cushite wife. They go so far as to entreat God on the matter, questioning whether or not Moses is the only prophet that the Lord has in Israel if he behaves in such a way (marrying a foreigner).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s response? He strikes Miriam with leprosy for seven days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;hx:overflow-x-auto hx:mt-6 hx:flex hx:flex-col hx:rounded-lg hx:border hx:py-4 hx:px-4 hx:border-gray-200 hx:contrast-more:border-current hx:contrast-more:dark:border-current hx:border-blue-200 hx:bg-blue-100 hx:text-blue-900 hx:dark:border-blue-200/30 hx:dark:bg-blue-900/30 hx:dark:text-blue-200&#34;&gt;
  &lt;p class=&#34;hx:flex hx:items-center hx:font-medium&#34;&gt;&lt;svg height=16px class=&#34;hx:inline-block hx:align-middle hx:mr-2&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;path stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; d=&#34;M13 16h-1v-4h-1m1-4h.01M21 12a9 9 0 11-18 0 9 9 0 0118 0z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;Note&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;div class=&#34;hx:w-full hx:min-w-0 hx:leading-7&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;hx:mt-6 hx:leading-7 hx:first:mt-0&#34;&gt;&lt;p&gt;God doesn&amp;rsquo;t oppose Moses&amp;rsquo; interracial marriage here, but rather He opposes Miriam challenging Moses&amp;rsquo; authority on account of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New Testament&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;new-testament&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#new-testament&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paul tells us in Galatians 3:27-28, &amp;ldquo;For as many of you as have been baptized into Christ have put on Christ. There is neither Jew nor Greek, there is neither slave nor free, and there is neither male nor female, for you are all one in Christ Jesus. If you are Christ’s, then you are Abraham’s seed, and heirs according to the promise.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major claim of those who oppose interracial marriage is that God created nations, put borders between them, and we must maintain those borders. Never mind the nonsense of that claim from a historical perspective (I&amp;rsquo;m sure none of those people care about the borders of the Native Americans, for example, or any of the other massive border shifts that have happened throughout history). From a purely biblical perspective, Paul makes it clear here that the previous boundaries that would separate people are fully dissolved in Christ. There are now just two nations with which we concern ourselves: Citizens of the Kingdom of Heaven, and citizens of this world. Those in Christ, and those not. Sheep and goats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ethnicity is no barrier to marriage between two Christians. In fact, in his 2nd letter to the Corinthians, Paul repeats God&amp;rsquo;s command from the Old Testament:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do not be unequally yoked together with unbelievers. For what fellowship has righteousness with unrighteousness? What communion has light with darkness? What agreement has Christ with Belial? Or what part has he who believes with an unbeliever? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;cite&gt;2 Corinthians 6:14-15, MEV&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Paul, it is not sinful for an Asian woman and an Aboriginal man to get married, or a white man and a black woman, or whatever other ethnic combination you want. The sin, for Paul (who was writing under the inspiration of God the Holy Ghost), is when a believer marries an unbeliever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again, God&amp;rsquo;s concern is not for your physical bloodline. For all men are created by God, given life and sustained by Him, and all men descend from His sons Adam and Noah. All bloodlines belong to the Lord. All were created by Him. And all were redeemed by the blood of His son Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;God&amp;rsquo;s concern is your faithfulness. He does not want you to be involved with anything that will lead you away from Him. I promise you that the podcasts you listen to, the movies you watch, and the books you read are of much more concern to the Lord than the skin color of your Christian spouse.&lt;/p&gt;

      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
