<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lutheran Answers – Mormons</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/answers/cults/mormons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mormons on Lutheran Answers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	  <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/answers/cults/mormons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      
        
      
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Are Mormons Christians?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/answers/cults/mormons/are-mormons-christians/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 20:44:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/answers/cults/mormons/are-mormons-christians/</guid>
      <description>
        
        
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/answers/mormons.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mormons&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No, members of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints are not Christians.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many Mormons are under the impression that they are the true Christians who have joined the true church of Jesus Christ as restored by Joseph Smith after a great apostasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, however, couldn’t be further from the truth. Mormons are actually members of a heretical non-Christian cult and are destined for eternity in Outer Darkness if they do not repent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Major Problems with Mormonism&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;major-problems-with-mormonism&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#major-problems-with-mormonism&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this section I will outline some of the biggest problems with Mormonism and the things that keep them outside of the true, saving faith of Jesus Christ. Please note this section will deal with salvific issues that Mormons face – I.E. the things that prevent them from entering Heaven (the Celestial Kingdom in Mormonese), and will ultimately resign them to eternal damnation (outer darkness).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Mormon Jesus&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;the-mormon-jesus&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#the-mormon-jesus&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem with Mormonism is the problem with their Jesus. Mormons will tell you that they worship the same Jesus that other Christians do. But that isn’t true. These are the issues with the Mormon view of Jesus Christ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Unitarianism&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;unitarianism&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#unitarianism&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mormons are Unitarian heretics who deny the Trinity. They believe that Jesus is a completely separate being with a separate substance from the Father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They believe that both Jesus and actually Satan are literal children born of a physical, conjugal relation of Heavenly Father (what they call The Father) and Heavenly Mother (a being that does not exist).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because they believe in an ontologically different Jesus, they must – literally and necessarily – be worshipping a different Jesus than other Christians. This is generally hard for unitarians to understand because they say they believe the Bible and use the same name we do for Jesus – so why isn’t it the same?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well let’s say that when I talk about Velma from Scooby-Doo, I’m referencing this nerdy brunette from the 70s:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;old-velma.webp&#34; alt=&#34;old Velma&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when you talk about Velma, you’re talking about the Indian Velma from Mindy Kaling’s HBO series:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;new-velma.png&#34; alt=&#34;new Velma&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are obviously talking about two different characters. They look different, act different, are in different settings. They just share names. One could argue that the newer Velma is just an imposter TV show wearing a Scooby-Doo skin suit to try and trade off of the good name that series earned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s like that. The Mormon Jesus, as they define Him, may have the same name and claim the same setting and attributes of Jesus, but it’s simply a poor copy attempting to trade on Jesus’ good name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;A better example&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;a-better-example&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#a-better-example&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since this article was originally written and published, I have conceived of an even better example than the Velma one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we both agree that our favorite movie is Ghostbusters, and we are both fans of the same movie, but when I say “Ghostbusters” I’m talking about this movie, from 1984:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ghostbusters.gif&#34; alt=&#34;OG Ghost Busters&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And when you say “Ghostbusters” you’re talking about this movie, from 2016:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;galbusters.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Fake Ghost Busters&#34;  loading=&#34;lazy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are we talking about the same movie? Are we fans of the same movie? But both movies have similar plots, they have a similar cast of characters, and even the same title and logo!?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet these two movies are not the same movie. They’re different movies. And you can’t say that we’re both talking about the same movie just because they have the same name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same thing with Jesus. You can put Jesus in your church’s name until you’re blue in the face, you can ascribe to him all the different genealogical and historical details you want, but if we fundamentally disagree about who He is, then we are talking about different Jesuses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Arianism&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;arianism&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#arianism&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Mormons are also Arian heretics. That is, they believe Jesus is just a man. In fact, they’re Super-Arians because they believe that Heavenly Father is also just a man who lived super duper good and was transformed into a god by his father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mormons maintain that God Himself is not a distinct being from man, but that men can become gods themselves. This applies to each person of the Godhead – who have already achieved deification – as well as to each and every individual on earth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is another way in which Mormons are worshipping an entirely different being than Christians, just with the same name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;A False Plan of Salvation&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;a-false-plan-of-salvation&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#a-false-plan-of-salvation&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Mormon Plan of Salvation, as they call it, is heavily dependent on your own works. Mormons believe that Jesus came to be an example to us, not to live vicariously for us. They also believe that He died so that we could be given a chance at Heaven, and He rose from the dead so that we might be resurrected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Mormonism, there is no conquering of death. There is no eternal remission of sin. There is no subjugation of the devil and this world. There is only Jesus offering you a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a missionary put it to me this way: You really need a new job. Jesus knows a guy at the company and puts in a good word to get you an interview. But now that you have the interview it is up to you to interview well enough to get the job. And once you get the job it’s up to you to work hard enough to be promoted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and how exactly do you work hard enough?
In addition to the 10 commandments, Mormons add an additional ~600 other commands that must be kept in order to achieve perfection and reach the Celestial Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The breaking of these commands is sin, and each sin pulls you away from perfection. Mormons often quote Matthew 5:48, saying that Christ commands us, “&lt;a href=&#34;https://beyeperfect.org/&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Be Ye Perfect&lt;svg class=&#34;hx:inline hx:rtl:rotate-270 hx:align-baseline&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
 &lt;path d=&#34;m9.1716 7.7574h7.0711m0 0v7.0711m0-7.0711-8.4853 8.4853&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;” here and now in this life. Those who are not perfect cannot attain all that Heavenly Father has for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ibis.utah.gov/ibisph-view/indicator/complete_profile/SuicDth.htm&#34;target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;It is no wonder Utah’s suicide rate is 50% higher than the national average&lt;svg class=&#34;hx:inline hx:rtl:rotate-270 hx:align-baseline&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-width=&#34;2&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34;&gt;
 &lt;path d=&#34;m9.1716 7.7574h7.0711m0 0v7.0711m0-7.0711-8.4853 8.4853&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Minor Problems with Mormonism&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;minor-problems-with-mormonism&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#minor-problems-with-mormonism&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This section will focus on other oddities of Mormonism that don’t make much sense. These things aren’t necessarily salvific issues, but I’m sure that some of them can become that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Universal Salvation&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;universal-salvation&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#universal-salvation&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mormons believe that everyone will be saved. They have three levels of Heaven: The telestial, terrestrial, and celestial. Every single person will end up in one of the three levels of heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;You are sealed to your family, but it’s pointless.&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;you-are-sealed-to-your-family-but-its-pointless&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#you-are-sealed-to-your-family-but-its-pointless&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Heaven: Mormonism believes that you have to be sealed to your family if you want to spend eternity with them. Except you being sealed to your spouse doesn’t guarantee anything because they might not make it as far up in Heaven as you, and only those in the Celestial Kingdom get to spend forever with their families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Women have no future in heaven&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;women-have-no-future-in-heaven&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#women-have-no-future-in-heaven&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Women in Mormon heaven exist only to be bred by their husbands to create spirit children. Also, if you are a woman, and you’re sealed to your husband, and you both make it to the celestial kingdom, and you both become gods, you might not be his only bride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, it is up to the husband to call you up to that level, so he may leave you behind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if you are his only bride, and he does call you up, and you both do get a planet, your only role in that planet will be producing his offspring. He gets to be the one who is actually god.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Other Issues&lt;span class=&#34;hx:absolute hx:-mt-20&#34; id=&#34;other-issues&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;a href=&#34;#other-issues&#34; class=&#34;subheading-anchor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Permalink for this section&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are tons of other issues, such as literary and historical problems with Mormon holy books, the character of Joseph Smith, other beliefs and values of the church.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are too many to list here, so I advise you go read something like the CES Letter or check out resources like Truth In Love Ministries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the first of a four part episode I did with Rev. Mark Parsons of Truth in Love Ministries on the LDS faith:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NIu--rbmaOs?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;


      </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
